I'm going to show you seven different
methods on how to join granny squares
and we're going to get started right
[Applause]
now hi guys welcome back to my channel
my name is Tiffany Hansen thank you so
much for joining me today in this video
I'm going to show you seven that's right
seven different techniques different
methods that you can use to join granny
squares and some of them are really cool
they're really different and exciting
and I can't wait to share that with you
if at any point in this video you do
like what you see please push that
thumbs up button and if you haven't yet
subscribe to my channel and click the
Bell that way you don't miss any of my
videos I try to release a brand new
video every single Friday covering a
wide range of different types of crochet
projects tips and tricks fun giveaways
and you're not going to want to miss out
the only things you need to join granny
squares will be the crochet hook that
you use to make the granny square a yarn
needle or tapestry needle even if you're
not doing a whip Stitch you're going to
need that to weave in all of your ends
anyway with the project a pair of
scissors the yarn that you want to use
to join the granny squares together
whether that yarn be the same color as
the granny squares themselves to create
a camouflage effect or a completely
different color for a pop or dramatic
effect which is really cool too and
honestly you may want some Stitch
markers or R markers to hold the corners
in place that way your granny squares
don't shift in the process of you
joining the them together cuz that's
never
fun but really that's all you need so
once you have everything or if you want
just a pad and paper and let's Dive
Right into method number one on how to
join granny squares the first method
that we are going to use is the whip
stitch in one Loop only so this is the
most common sewing method for joining
two pieces together we begin by looking
at our granny squares here or looking at
your work and identifying which side you
would consider your right side and which
side you would consider your wrong side
if you've never heard of this before
your right side would be considered the
piece of your work or the side of your
work that you want presented out to
people when it comes to certain projects
though such as the general granny square
both sides of your work look fairly
identical how you would identify the
right side and wrong side of this
particular project is look at the
outermost stitches and you'll see here
that my V stitches are more faced
forward where if I turn this over those
same V stitches are now facing downward
so this side of my work would be
considered the wrong side or the back of
the work other pieces are a lot easier
to identify what the f front side is if
you're doing front posts then they're
sticking out on one side and they're not
showing on the back or the other side or
in certain granny squares you have 3D
flowers or some kind of stitch that is
popping out the front you'll know that
is considered the right side and the
other side of the work that does not
have that 3D bump or 3D Stitch detail
would be considered the wrong side or
the back so you got to identify which
side is the front side which side is the
back side especially for the whip Stitch
because what we're going to be doing is
we're going to be putting the two front
sides or right sides of the work
together in this case here I see my V
stitches and I see my V stitches so
these are both my right
sides and I'm going to put them together
I want my right sides together and then
the wrong side facing out wrong side
facing out great the whip Stitch we are
using a yarn needle tapestry needle to
do our join in this case you're going to
want to cut enough of the yarn that you
are using for your join so that way it's
easy to work with you're able to get
through the piece hopefully but not too
long where you're creating a tangle mess
in the process of doing your join if you
need to add more yarn to continue your
join that's just fine depending on what
you are joining together your granny
square Corner might look very different
some granny square corners will be a
chain three some will be a chain two and
some will just be a chain one just to
get you over to that work you're going
to want to find the centermost piece so
if it's a chain three to get around your
corner then you're going to look for
that second or middl most chain and
that's where you will begin if it's a
chain two to get around then look for
the second chain and that will be the
chain that helps you along the this side
or the top and the first chain will be
the last Stitch of this side right here
okay and if it is just one chain then go
in that centermost chain chain and
that's like the perfect chain indicator
of this is the corner if there is no
chain at all such as maybe they're doing
a fan or a shell to go around the corner
then just find the centermost Stitch and
go on the top of that stitch in this
case I have a chain two so I'm going to
use the second
chain look at the two pieces that are
together and you're going to find the
back Loop only so here's my two chains
so I'm using the second chain
here here is my V stitch and I'm going
to go in the back Loop only of my V
stitch look at the other piece of work
second chain here find the V stitch and
I'm going to go through the front Loop
of this Stitch which would be the back
Loop if I were to look at it from from
this
side pull through
leaving enough of a tail for you to
weave in and clean up your
ends tie a
knot and it doesn't have to be too tight
just in case you make a mistake you can
have it tight enough but always secure
it
later take your yarn
needle find the next Stitch down the
next
V go in the back
Loop find the next Stitch down on the
other side find the V stitch go through
the front
Loop and
pull then you'll take the yarn and
you'll bring it over to the other side
and again you'll start on the exact same
side finding the next Stitch over back
Loop a joining Stitch front Loop there
and
pull there we go then bring it over and
repeat now some work some granny squares
will be identical like you're just
working the exact same granny square
stitch in every granny square maybe
you'll change up the colors a little bit
but they're all the same exact pattern
meaning that you'll have the exact same
number of stitches on each side of the
work in which case your stitches will be
a one to one
ratio every Stitch will have a matching
identical
stitch for it on the other side okay
there are some or if you are working a
pattern where you're using different
granny squares together that's beautiful
I love the technique but sometimes
there'll be a different number of
stitches on one side of the granny
square to the other side of the granny
square in which case the easiest way to
do that is to grab Stitch markers so
here I would grab two Stitch
markers I'd find the very first and very
last Stitch that I'm going to be working
up for that
side so I would go here which is the
first chain of the chain two because
that's the last Stitch of that
side and I would put one in the
first that way it's not shifting and
then I would just make sure as I'm going
along okay I'm just need to keep these
two pieces in line with each other keep
them together and then I'm just going to
work these two stitches okay so new
Stitch down but oh it looks like it's
the same stitch on the other side that I
just put a stitch in okay I'm just going
to keep it in line that way
it is going to stay together the way
that I want it to because in that case
if you did try to go a one: one ratio
with your stitches your work might
endend up like offset like that or you
run out of room on one side or it's
bunched up and it just it just doesn't
look right so you want to keep your work
in line with each other and hopefully
your stitches are a one to one ratio
where it's next Stitch down it has an
adjoining up that's the Stitch match for
it but again if it
doesn't just keep things in line okay so
in this case we are working the back
Loop only of both sides again if I was
looking over here that would be the back
Loop only of my Stitch and we're just
going
over and back
through and then over and back through
and that is known as the whip stitch in
one Loop here's what it looks like if I
were to tighten that there's the front
wait this is the front here's the front
this is what it would look like
and this would be the back of the work I
think this Stitch would look really
pretty if the yarn that you were using
to join this the two pieces of work
together was the exact same color as one
of the outermost colors or preferably if
both of the granny squares ended in the
exact same color you would use that same
color to join them together and it would
be a very it would be a very pretty join
the second joining method that we're
going to go over is the whip Stitch in
both Loops so again we're going to find
the front side or the right side of our
granny squares or our work remember that
to identify the front side sometimes you
have to look at the outermost stitches
and see find your V stitches if your V
stitches are facing up that's the right
side of your work if they're facing down
you're looking at the back or the wrong
side of your work okay once you identify
which sides are your right sides or your
front sides you want those two sides to
be facing each other revealing the wrong
side or the back side of the work on
both sides the whip Stitch both Loops is
also done with a yarn needle tapestry
needle again making sure you have enough
yarn cut out to work the piece as best
you can without being too much where
you're creating Tangles all right we're
going to find the corner most Stitch and
we're going to go underneath both
Loops find the corner most Stitch find
both
Loops there we
go and then you would tie your knot
making sure you're leaving a long enough
tail for you to weave in your end at the
end of the
project and then what you're going to do
is you're going to go next Stitch down
if you need to separate your work to
identify that find your V
stitch go through the side of the work
underneath both of those loops
all the way across to the adjoining
side under both loops and
Pull and take the yarn go over the
work find the next Stitch down under
both Loops so go through the
front underneath both
Loops joining stitch on the other side
underneath both
loops and pull
then over and
continue next Stitch
down this technique definitely moves
fast and will help you get
through
quicker if you're going through a chain
one I would still go under both Loops I
wouldn't go under the whole work I would
just go under two Loops leaving one loop
on the bottom so you have two on the
top and straight
across okay
so this is the wrong side this is the
back of the work this is how the back of
the work will look I'm pulling it and
pulling my yarn
tighter so this is what the join will
look like on the back of the
work and this this is what the join will
look like on the front of the work you
can see the yarn the join so in this
case again I would probably pick a yarn
to use that is the same color as one of
the outermost colors just so it Blends
better and is not such an eyesore as an
opposite color or a completely different
random color or just a color that is not
one of these two outermost colors that
is what I would pick and if you did that
I think the join would look really
pretty and works very well all right and
that that looks great works up fast and
that is the whip stitch in both Loops
the next join that we're going to work
is known as the single crochet join
method so we want to actually have the
front sides or the right sides of our
work facing outwards so we're going to
take these
two and put them
together like that so front side
outermost side front side outermost side
and then we're going to move them to the
side and we will work them as one
together I'm going to go ahead and I'm
going to work them this way just
hopefully to be a better better visual
for you use the crochet hook that you
used when making your granny squares
it's just easiest that way you don't
need to go up a size or down a size
unless you choose
to okay grab the yarn that you want want
to use to join these two pieces start
with a tail long enough for you to weave
in your end at the end make your slip
knot attach your crochet hook and we're
ready to begin so start in the corner
most chain or Stitch we're going to find
that second Stitch here or that middle
Stitch find the V and insert our crochet
hook in the back Loop only all right
find the adjoining piece find the corner
find the middl most or the Stitch that
you want to use depending on if these
are identical you're using the same
Stitch or if they're different then just
find that corner Stitch and you're going
to go in the front Loop only just like
that now why it says front Loop or I say
front Loop is if I were to turn it it
would be the back Loop of this like
looking at it from this way would be
back Loop and then front Loop so I
basically want to work just those two
Loops that are touching each other or
that would be considered back Loops of
both sides of the work yarn over pull
that yarn through both sides so now I
have two loops on my crochet hook and
then yarn over again and pull through
those two Loops for a single crochet
stitch next Stitch down find the next V
stitch
V back Loop only
on the other side find the next V
stitch and go to the front
Loop yarn over pull through both yarn
over pull through both Loops for a
single crochet and then you would just
continue to work this what I like about
the single crochet join is that you can
have the yarn just feeding from the ske
that you were using and you just keep
going there's no having to add any
additional yarn when you run out such as
you would if you were working the whip
Stitch right let me get a little bit
further in here if you get to a chain
one just find the loop that is closest
to you and work that Loop you're not
going to go under all Loops here
all right let me get a little bit
further and then I'll show you what it
looks like okay so pull that tight so I
can REM remove my crochet hook pull
these strings out of the way so this is
what it will look like it has a raised
join you you see the loops you see the
Stitches the you see the V stitches here
which is very pretty and that is your
join looking at it from the front side I
really like this look I think it would
look very flattering if you had either
the same color used either the same
color here for the join to blend it but
I also think it would look really
beautiful having this color be a pop
color or a different color to accentuate
the joining of these two granny squares
here's what the back looks like it's
also a very beautiful join here either
in a a different color or the same color
used for one of the outermost colors of
the granny square it's very pretty very
clean so even if you liked this join
look better than the V stitches here all
you would have to do to achieve this
look is instead of having the right side
facing outward you'd flip this and have
the wrong sides facing outward and then
the side that would be presented out to
people would look like this
join the fourth method that we're going
to use to join granny squares or join
pieces together is known as the reverse
single crochet stitch it's a little more
tricky but the appearance looks like a
braided cord which is really pretty and
a really cool effect to the join itself
so what we're going to do is we're going
to use the crochet hook that we used to
make our granny squares not going to
change that up unless you choose to find
the color of yarn that you would like to
use start with a tail long enough for
you to weave even your
ends create a slip knot and attach your
crochet hook now in this case the
braided cord look will be the look that
you want facing out to people so you're
going to want that on the right side of
your blanket so finding the right side
of your granny square we're going to
keep those on the outside of this
join and the wrong sides of the work
will be the sides that are facing each
other okay we're going to actually begin
in the opposite corner than you would
start and we're going to work backwards
I know it's weird but it's called the
reverse single crochet stitch so finding
the corner most Stitch we're going to
actually work in the back Loops only so
finding the back Loop of that V
stitch finding the corner this is the
corner Stitch I'm using V I'm going to
use the front Loop of that side so the
two Loops touching each other are now
going to be
joined okay yarn over pull through yarn
over pull through and then we're going
to go backwards so finding the Stitch
the V stitch that's behind
us going to go into the back Loop
only finding the next Stitch down front
Loop only there y yarn
over pull
through yarn
over pull through both Loops all right
let's keep going so you can actually see
the effect I'm going to take this little
tail I'm going to tuck that tail out of
the way okay
so finding the next Loop enter into that
loop back Loop only next V stitch front
Loop yarn
over pull through both of those sides
leaving you two Loops yarn over pull
through both Loops let me get a little
further down and then you'll see what it
looks like so next V stitch back Loop
only looking at the back front Loop of
the next
Stitch yarn over
pull through yarn over pull through now
this method does take a little bit
longer because it feels a little awkward
it feels a little
weird going backwards reverse so take
your time with this one until you can
get the feel for it and then you can
move a little bit
faster you are purely doing this
technique for that cord look to achieve
that cord look which does look really
cool pull
through pull through
okay so I'm going to remove my crochet
hook so you can see what's going on
here so this is the look that cord
look pull these pieces apart so you can
really
see and you can see with this cord
look how depending on the granny squares
that you created
and this this could look really pretty
this could be very defining for these
granny square pieces absolutely I love
this cord look it's very very neat very
different I I think this would look
really great if it was the same color
kind of camouflaging with the granny
squares themselves but yet that cord
look would still have a very beautiful
definition also I think that if you used
this as a pop color power color or just
stick out join color for your granny
squares that could look really cool too
here's what it looks like on the
back it looks very up and down up and
down join which also looks very clean so
if you like this look you can always use
this on the front of your work as well
the fifth join method that we're going
to go over is known as the slip stitch
on the front side of the work this
Stitch is very pretty it's an attractive
chain stitch that you will see on the
front side of your work so we begin by
identifying the front sides of our
granny squares that's going to stay
facing upward grab the yarn that you
choose to join these two pieces together
start with a tail long enough for you to
weave in your ends create a slip knot
attach your crochet hook we're ready to
begin so finding the corner we're going
to work the back Loops only so in this
corner chain going to go in the back
Loop
only a joining Corner
[Music]
chain the back Loop only of that
chain going to yarn
over pull through both sides and also
pull through the loop on our crochet
hook we want the yarn that is attached
to our skce to kind of remain in the
back of the work so also let's move that
tail okay so next
Stitch back Loop
only next
Stitch the back Loop
only yarn
over pull
through one you might have to swivel
your hook your claw in order to get
through those sides and then pull that
Loop through the loop that's on your
crochet hook you just want to keep one
loop on your crochet hook okay so next
Stitch back
Loop keep that yarn behind the work next
Stitch here back
Loop yarn over pull through and then I
will kind of like rotate or turn turn my
crochet
hook to get
through get
through and
through back
loop back
Loop yarn over pull
through pull through pull
through okay let me get further down so
that way you can really see what's going
on
here now you might be noticing that as
I'm going along I'm going from top down
into the Stitch here and instead of
going from the top down into the Stitch
here I'm going underneath it and through
the loop that way then yarning over
pulling through pulling through pulling
through the reason I'm doing that is I'm
basically working this as if I had
sandwiched these two pieces
together and then how this will
work you want that yarn there is it'll
be back Loop like that that's basically
how I am working those stitches
together then yarn over pull through
all keeping that yarn
behind go
okay so let's see what this looks
like this is what the join will end up
looking like so this would be the front
of your
work and you can absolutely see those
clear V stitches they lay flat opposed
to the single crochet join where it was
it did stick out it was more pronounced
this lays flat against the work this
would look beautiful in either the same
color as a camouflage color join or
again it would look great as an outside
color or a pop of color if I were to use
maybe this charcoal gray on the outside
it would really pop and create a very
defining line defining join between
these two granny
squares the back looks like this and
this line is very straight this
direction it doesn't go side to side so
much it's more of straight line this way
so if you find this attractive or really
like that look you could absolutely use
the same color as one of these outermost
colors or in a a pop of color like this
charcoal and that would look really
clean as well well so that is known as
the slip stitch on the front side of the
work the sixth joining method for
joining granny squares is called slip
stitch on the back side and I actually
favor this Stitch a lot if you are
wanting a join that is invisible so
finding the front sides going to flip
those over so we are looking at the back
sides of the work or the wrong side and
then you're going to join those
together so in the middle you got the
two front sides facing each other and on
the outside you have the backs or the
wrong sides facing outward taking the
yarn that you would like to use to join
these two granny squares starting with a
long enough tail for us to weave in our
ends at the end of the project creating
our slip knot touching our crochet
hook okay finding the corner most Stitch
but this time we're working in the front
Loops I know it's different it's it's
going to feel a little different but
once you get used to it it'll work up
quickly so front
Loop front
Loop or the outermost Loop outermost
Loop yarn over pull the yarn all the way
through and then slip stitch okay next
Stitch over I like to use my claw a lot
here so underneath the front
Loop go to the other side finding the V
stitch going to go underneath that Loop
so the two Loops that are touching or
closest to each other are going to be
left behind we're not touching those
Loops yarn over pull that yarn all the
way through and all the way through the
loop on our crochet
hook that Loop
even on those chain ones I'm only going
underneath that one Loop
and eventually you will get the hang of
it and start picking up some speed
all right
so removing my crochet
hook so this is what work will look like
on the back side the wrong side because
again these are the two wrong sides of
our work you've got those V stitches
that were created right
there and the other side
so that's what it will look like on the
wrong side but check out what happens
when I flip it to look at the right
side pull this a little bit
tighter what you see here is no
join if I were to spread these out you
would see the join but if I were to
relax it it literally looks like my
granny square is right next to the other
granny square that's what it looks like
it's hard to kind of see it
in there see you don't see the join at
all it's so neat they're connected see
they're connected but the way that
they're connected you don't see any
joint at all it just literally looks
like the granny square is budded right
next to the other granny square and that
is known as the slip stitch on backs
side the last join method that I'm going
to go over the seventh join method is
known as slip stitch and chain now to be
honest when I first saw this particular
join method it blew my mind because it
reminded me that there's never a set way
of doing things you can absolutely think
out of the box you can absolutely just
take things to a whole other level and
we forget to do that sometimes and when
I saw this it it really inspired me and
I hope it inspires you too if you have
not seen this technique before so you
find the side of the work the right side
of the work and you're going to take
your crochet
hook take your yarn the yarn of choice
that you want to use begin with a long
enough tail for you to weave in your
ends create a slip knot and attach your
crochet
hook okay so I'm going to work this way
with the yarn or with the granny squares
being one on top of each other opposed
to this direction so I'm going to go
this way going to take the first granny
square or piece of work find the corner
most piece and you're going to work
underneath both Loops if you are working
in a chain feel free to just work
underneath the whole thing to make it
easier on you to begin if you are
working the chain within the side then
you would want to work underneath both
loops and not or two loops and not
underneath the whole work so just slip
stitch that's all we want want to do
there find the other side of the work
we're going to chain either two or chain
three it's totally up to you chain more
if you want but I'm going to chain two
one two and then I'm going to find the
corner most stitch on this side and it's
easier for me to go underneath two loops
with with the yarn that I used here so
just under two loops and then slip
stitch all right and then chain two one
two or chain three if you change three
here skip either one or skip two if you
change two I would skip just one stitch
if you chained three I would skip two
stitches and then slip stitch underneath
two Loops both Loops of the next
Stitch then chain two one
two skip a stitch slip stitch both Loops
of the next
Stitch slip stitch chain two one
two skip a stitch this is a chain one
but I'm still going
to go under two Loops one loop on the
bottom two loops on the top and slip
stitch chain two one
two move
Tail right skipping the next Stitch slip
stitch both Loops of the next
Stitch
right let me work that a little bit so
you can see so one two
chains skipping the next Stitch slip
stitch in the following
Stitch one
2 skipping the next Stitch slip stitch
in the
[Music]
following now if you want to you could
even just work these two pieces side by
side one
two skip slip
stitch one two okay looking at the other
side
skip slip
stitch one two
stitch however that looks best works
best feels best for you do that all
right so moving my crochet hook and now
we're going to to look at this and I'm
going to actually
remove my mat underneath so you can
identify or see it a little bit better
I've got like a dark
wood color underneath
here but then if you do this method the
join
creates this like V stitch kind of
look between your two granny squares and
it is very very cool and so your join
has more personality it has more detail
more characteristic and again it's one
of those areas where you can play and
either use the same exact color as one
of these outermost stitches or you can
use a completely different color and
have this be very detailed very bold
very defining for your granny squares
and it just creates even more to the
whole project it makes it look more
complicated complex so that is the slip
stitch and
chain okay here I wanted to show you
what you do once you have reached the
end of the granny square that you are
working so you find the last Corner most
Stitch of that
side right now I just working the single
crochet join method it's just an easier
method but you would use this exact same
technique for every single method that I
showed you
today you find the next
two granny squares that you want to join
to this particular
panel you find that corner most
Stitch and you work in that one
depending on which Stitch you are
working find that corner most stitch on
the other granny
square work in that
one pull that yarn tight
and then continue on and then you just
continue working the same exact join
method on these two granny squares or
these two sections you were
joining and you continue on and what
that will end up looking
like is let me get a little bit further
here it end up looking like
this so you just continued right on
in this case with this being the single
crochet join so this is what you'll look
like now some people struggle when it
comes to this part and they Wonder oh
gosh what do I do to get over this when
joining these two sections well let me
go ahead and show you how to do that now
Okay so we've worked this whole join
together
joining these two panels together
together we're coming up to this join
what we do is we will join those last
two stitches on this side of the
work so joining those last two stitches
we will chain one to hop over this join
and then find the very next stitches for
that corner Stitch that have not been
touched yet
and start working the join
there all
right I like to add that chain one to
hop over the
join to help provide some room here let
me get a little bit further so it makes
sense
okay lay that
flat there we go awesome so I like to
add that chain one to hop over this join
right here because if you don't then
I've noticed that these two will scrunch
together and it doesn't lay flat like I
would like if you don't want to add that
chain one then don't go for it do
whatever works best for you but I like
to add that chain one right there to
help my work lay flat if you are working
a different Stitch you would do the same
thing chain one right there to hop over
or if you are noticing that you need
your work is still bunching add another
chain but that seems to work out really
well for me and I hope that you see that
I hope that that looks good to you as
well but that is it that's how I get
over that join there to start joining
this
Direction and lastly I wanted to show
you if you were to use the slip stitch
chain join method how you would go about
expanding from these joining these two
granny squares to moving over to the
next granny squares that you will join
to this panel and then I will show you
how you will cross over using that same
join Method All right so looking at
these two granny squares right now that
we are joining with the slip stitch
chain method you will reach the end here
so I'm doing the Skip One Stitch and
then slip stitch into the
next but I don't want to leave a big gap
here to the next panel or to the next
granny square what I'm going to do is
I'm going to close off this particular
join before I go to the next and what I
mean by that is I will do my chain two
cuz that's what I'm doing
here and
then I know I already used this Stitch
and there's only one more stitch on this
side because this chain is part of this
side but I'm just going to go into that
very last Stitch space to seal off this
panel run
over pull
through pull through okay so I will
literally just end these two joins with
a flat chain two slip stitch then I will
take these two granny squares that I
want to attach over and I'll chain two
one two and then I'll come to this side
and I will slip
stitch and then I'll chain two one two
and I'll come to this corner and slip
stitch so underneath two
Loops so corner corner corner corner
slip stitch and then I will continue the
join chain
two Skip One Stitch slip
stitch chain
two Skip One Stitch and slip
stitch so that is how I would go from
these two joins or joining these two
with the slip stitch chain method adding
two more panels on to complete this
section all right so that's that's how I
would do that now let's look at how we
would then cross section using this join
method okay so here's where we're at
right now let's pretend that we are
working the slip stitch chain join
method here I've worked these two panels
all the way along this side and now I'm
starting to work the cross sections to
join this way as well so I'm working
that slip stitch chain me method so one
two I'm going to find the corner most
Stitch here before I pass over this join
and I'm going to close
there slip
stitch just like I did when I was
finishing off these two and about to
cross over to the next two want to make
sure that it is a solid line there find
the corner most Stitch of this one right
here
even if you're not able to skip a stitch
to get to this
Stitch you want to be right
here there we
go and slip stitch so now I have
completely finished the join for these
two granny squares together here I'm
going to chain two one two I'm going to
hop over this joint and find the
diagonal chain here the diagonal Corner
Stitch I'm going to slip stitch in that
Stitch chain two one two and then I'm
going to go to this granny square here
and find the corner stitch for that
one there we go going to slip stitch in
that one and then then I'm set up to
continue doing the skip a stitch slip
stitch into the next Stitch over pattern
joining these two granny squares so
chain two one two skip a stitch next
Stitch slip stitch so this is what that
will look
like these colors are probably not the
best colors most flattering colors to
utilize this Stitch with but you get the
idea of what it will look like if you
were to use other colors but here we
have a cross there for that crosssection
and then you would just continue working
that pattern all the way across that's
it hope that made sense well that's
everything that I have found so far if
you know of any other joining stitches
or joining methods that I did not
mention please put those in the comments
below I would love to hear it's just
very exciting to see different methods
different techniques and different ways
of doing something I also tried to make
sure this video was very comprehensive
so that way if you have never joined
Gran granny squares or even joined two
pieces of crocheted work together that
you were able to figure out how to start
how to stop how to join and even the
crossover of when you're joining the
other direction cuz often that is the
most confusing part of the whole the
whole thing so I really hope that I
answered all your questions if I missed
anything please mention it in the
comment section below uh ask the
question or just if you saw that I
missed something and you're like ah I
would love to add something to this
tutorial just add it in the comment
section below I would love to hear and
learn off of you as well it's always
such a learning experience this whole
thing and I just appreciate it so much
well thank you so much for joining me
today thank you for crocheting with me I
hope you had fun if you enjoyed this
video you might also really enjoy these
videos right here also check out this
video which is just a recommended video
for you to watch I hope you have the
best day and I will see you with my next
video bye guys